samedelman.com 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy | Sam Edelman

This policy describes how SamEdelman.com collects, uses, and shares personal information. SamEdelman.com is a wholly owned division of Caleres, Inc. You can jump to particular topics by going to the headings below:

### Types Of Information We Collect

The following provides examples of the type of information that we collect from you and how we use that information.

### Context

| 

### Types of Data, Purpose for Collection, and Use of Data  
  
---|---  
Account Registration | We collect your name and contact information when you create an account. Accounts can be used for easy checkout and to save your preferences and transaction history.   
Email Interconnectivity | If you receive email from us, we use certain tools to capture data related to when you open our message, click on any links or banners it contains and make purchases.  
Employment | If you apply for a job posting, or become an employee, we collect information necessary to process your application or to retain you as an employee. This may include, among other things, your Social Security Number. Providing this information is required for employment.  
Feedback/Support | If you provide us feedback or contact us for support we will collect your name and e-mail address, as well as any other content that you send to us, in order to reply.  
Mailing List | When you sign up for one of our mailing lists we collect your email address or postal address.   
Order Placement | We collect your name, billing address, shipping address, e-mail address, phone number, and credit card number when you place an order for fulfillment and troubleshooting.  
Partner Promotion | We collect information that you provide as part of a co-branded promotion with another company.  
Surveys and Contests | When you participate in a survey or contest we collect information that you provide through that process. We use survey information to improve our services, and contest information for announcing winners. If the survey or contest is provided by a third party, the third party’s privacy policy applies to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information.   
Third Party Tracking | We participate in behavior-based advertising. This means that a third party uses technology (e.g., a cookie) to collect information about your use of our website so that they can provide advertising about products and services tailored to your interests. That advertising may appear either on our websites, or on other websites. You can opt-out of receiving advertising based upon your browsing behavior from some network advertising companies by going to the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/) and the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/) websites, although to completely prevent advertising based upon your browsing behavior you should also disable the cookies on your browser.  
Web logs | We collect information, including your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address (a number that is automatically assigned to a computer when the Internet is used), domain name, click-activity, referring website, and/or a date/time stamp for visitors.   
Cookies and first party tracking | We use cookies and clear GIFs. “Cookies” are small pieces of information that a website sends to a computer’s hard drive while a web site is viewed. We may use both session cookies (which expire once a web browser is closed) and persistent cookies (which stay on a device until deleted). Among other things, cookies allow us to provide a more personal and interactive experience and to improve our marketing efforts. Persistent cookies may be removed by following instructions provided by your browser. If you choose to disable cookies some areas or features of our websites may not work properly. We do not store personal information in the cookie.  
  
In addition to the information that we collect from you directly, we may also receive information about you from other sources, including third parties, business partners, our affiliates, or publicly available sources. For example, if you submit a job application, or become an employee, we may conduct a background check.

### Use And Processing Of Information

In addition to the purposes and uses described above, we use information in the following ways:

  * To identify you when you visit our websites or our stores.
  * To provide products and services or to process returns.
  * To improve our services and product offerings.
  * To streamline the checkout process.
  * To conduct analytics.
  * To respond to inquiries related to support, employment opportunities, or other requests.
  * To send marketing and promotional materials, including information relating to our products, services, sales, or promotions.
  * For internal administrative purposes, as well as to manage our relationships.

As discussed in the sections above, our collection and processing of your information is based in different contexts upon your consent, our need to perform a contract, our obligations under law, and/or our legitimate interest in conducting our business.

### Sharing Of Information

In addition to the specific situations discussed elsewhere in this policy, we disclose information in the following situations:

  1. ### Affiliates and Acquisitions.

We may share information with our corporate affiliates (e.g., parent company, sister companies, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control). If another company acquires our company, business, or our assets, we will also share information with that company.
  2. ### Other Disclosures with Your Consent.

We may ask if you would like us to share your information with other unaffiliated third parties who are not described elsewhere in this policy.
  3. ### Other Disclosures without Your Consent.

We may disclose information in response to subpoenas, warrants, or court orders, or in connection with any legal process, or to comply with relevant laws. We may also share your information in order to establish or exercise our rights, to defend against a legal claim, to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal activities, suspected fraud, safety of person or property, or a violation of our policies, or to comply with your request for the shipment of products to or the provision of services by a third party intermediary.
  4. ### Public.

You may have the opportunity to post comments, or reviews, in a public forum. If you decide to submit information on these pages, that information may be publically available.
  5. ### Partner Promotion.

We may offer contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions with third party partners. If you decide to enter a contest, sweepstakes, or promotion that is sponsored by a third party partner the information that you provide will be shared with us and with them. Their use of your information is not governed by this privacy policy.
  6. ### Service Providers.

We may share your information with service providers. Among other things service providers may help us to administer our website, conduct surveys, provide technical support, process payments, and assist in the fulfillment of orders.

### Your Choices

You can make the following choices regarding your personal information:

  1. ### Promotional Emails.

You may choose to provide us with your email address for the purpose of allowing us to send newsletters, surveys, offers, and other promotional materials to you, as well as targeted offers from third parties. You can stop receiving promotional emails by following the unsubscribe instructions in e-mails that you receive or by clicking [here](mailto:privacy@caleres.com). If you decide not to receive promotional emails, we may still send you service related communications.
  2. ### Promotional Mailings.

If at any time you do not want to receive promotional mailings from us you can remove yourself from our mailing lists by emailing us at ([Email Customer Service](mailto:privacy@caleres.com)) with "NO MAILINGS" in the subject line along with your name, address and zip code. Please note that our mailings are prepared in advance of their being sent. Although we will remove your name from our mailing list after receiving your request, you may still receive mailings from us that had been initiated prior to your name being removed.
  3. ### Changes To Your Personal Information.

We rely on you to update and correct your personal information. Our website allows you to modify or delete your account profile. You can make changes to other information by contacting us at the information below or by clicking [here](mailto:privacy@caleres.com). Note that we may keep historical information in our backup files as permitted by law. If our website does not permit you to update or correct certain information contact us at the address described below.
  4. ### Deletion Of Your Personal Information.

Typically we retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. You may, however, request information about how long we keep a specific type of information, or request that we delete your personal information by contacting us at the contact information below or by clicking [here.](mailto:privacy@caleres.com) In addition, we may keep your personal information as needed to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and/or enforce any of our agreements.
  5. ### Revocation of Consent.

If you revoke your consent for the processing of personal information then we may no longer be able to provide you services. In some cases, we may limit or deny your request to revoke consent if the law permits or requires us to do so, or if we are unable to adequately verify your identity. You may revoke consent to processing (where such processing is based upon consent) by contacting us at the contact information below.
  6. ### Access To Your Personal Information.

If required by law, upon request, we will grant you with reasonable access to the personal information that have about you. You may request access to your personal information by contacting us at the contact information below.
  7. ### Online Tracking.

We do not currently recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include "Do Not Track" instructions.
  8. ### California Residents.

California residents may be entitled to ask us for a notice describing what categories of personal information (if any) we share with third parties or affiliates for direct marketing. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of such notice, please submit a written request to us using the information in the “Contact Information” section below.

### How We Protect Personal Information

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is fully secure. While we use reasonable efforts to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information. In the event that we are required by law to inform you of any unauthorized access to your personal information we may notify you electronically, in writing, or by telephone, if permitted to do so by law.  
Our website permits you to create an account. When you do you will be prompted to create a password. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password, and you are responsible for any access to or use of your account by someone else that has obtained your password, whether or not such access or use has been authorized by you. You should notify us of any unauthorized use of your password or account.

### Miscellaneous

The following additional information relates to our privacy practices:

  * ### Transmission Of Information To Other Countries.

Your information may be processed in a foreign country where privacy laws may be less stringent than the laws in your country. Nonetheless, where possible we take steps to treat personal information using the same privacy principles that apply pursuant to the law of the country in which we first received your information. By submitting your personal information to us you agree to the transfer, storage and processing of your information in a country other than your country of residence including, but not necessarily limited to, the United States. If you would like more information concerning our attempts to apply the privacy principles applicable in one jurisdiction to data when it goes to another jurisdiction you can contact us using the contact information below.
  * ### Third Party Applications/Websites.

We have no control over the privacy practices of websites or applications that we do not own.
  * ### Children.

SamEdelman.com is not targeted to children. We will never knowingly request information from anyone under the age of 13 without parental consent.
  * ### Changes To This Privacy Policy.

We may change our privacy policy and practices over time.  
Option 1: To the extent that our policy changes in a material way, the policy that was in place at the time that you submitted personal information to us will generally govern that information unless we receive your consent to the new privacy policy. If at any point we decide to use your personal information in a manner different from what was stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by email. At that time, you will have a choice as to whether we use your information in this different manner.  
Option 2: Any material future changes or additions to the processing of personal information as described in this Policy affecting you will be communicated to you through an appropriate channel. For example, we may place a prominent notice on a product site or email you to let you know of an updated Policy.  
Option 3: If our information practices change in the future, we will post an updated policy on this Web site. You can tell if the policy has changed by checking the revision date. If we change the policy in a material way, we will provide appropriate notice to you.

### Contact Information

If you have any questions, comments, or complaints concerning our privacy practices please contact us at the appropriate address below. We will attempt to respond to your requests and to provide you with additional privacy-related information. 

Sam Edelman Customer Service  
8300 Maryland Ave.  
St. Louis, MO 63105  
1-888-889-9609  

If you are not satisfied with our response, and are in the European Union, you may have a right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority.

### Last Revised: 06/11/2018
